let javascriptquestions =
{   
    time : 30 , //in minutes
    questions: [
        {
            question: "1. What will be the output of the following code snippet var a = \"Scaler\" \n var result = a.substring(2, 4)\ndocument.write(result)",
            option1: "calculate by your self, i can't do it",
            option2: "cal",
            option3: "al",
            option4: "ali",
            correctresponse: "al",
            time: 1
        },
        {
            question: "2. What will be the output of the following code snippet console.log(halwa)",
            option1: "no halwa available !, please order on swiggy",
            option2: "halwa is not defined",
            option3: "no output",
            option4: "halwa",
            correctresponse: "halwa is not defined",
            time: 1
        },
        {
            question: "3. Pick the wrong",
            option1: "Primitive data types can store only a single value.",
            option2: "To store multiple and complex values, non-primitive data types are used",
            option3: "Object is a primitive data type",
            option4: "typeof of NaN will return a Number.",
            correctresponse: "Object is a primitive data type",
            time: 1
        },
        {
            question: "4. Pick the correct one",
            option1: " == is used to compare values while === is used to compare values and data type both",
            option2: "To store multiple and complex values, non-primitive data types are used",
            option3: "Object is a primitive data type",
            option4: "JS is java of internet",
            correctresponse: " == is used to compare values while === is used to compare values and data type both",
            time: 1
        },
        {
            question: "5. JavaScript is a ______ language.",
            option1: "boolean",
            option2: "statically typed language",
            option3: "very very very 100X tough",
            option4: "dynamically typed",
            correctresponse: "dynamically typed",
            time: 1
        },
        {
            question: "6. What is IIFE in JavaScript.",
            option1: "Award show to feature best JS devoloper",
            option2: " Immediately Invoked Function(IIFE) is a function that runs as soon as it is defined.",
            option3: "Immediately Invoked Function(IIFE) is a function to listen events",
            option4: "syntaxError- Immediately Invoked Function(IIFE) is not a function",
            correctresponse: " Immediately Invoked Function(IIFE) is a function that runs as soon as it is defined.",
            time: 1
        },
        {
            question: "7. What do you mean by strict mode in javascript and characteristics of javascript strict-mode",
            option1: "It is a new feature by which all forms of errors, including silent errors, will be thrown. As a result, debugging becomes a lot simpler.",
            option2: "it is a react component helps to render app and jsx",
            option3: "It is a feature which is only used in reactjs in rendering components",
            option4: "It is a new feature by which all forms of errors, including silent errors will be removed and the script is autocorrected",
            correctresponse: "It is a new feature by which all forms of errors, including silent errors, will be thrown. As a result, debugging becomes a lot simpler.",
            time: 1
        },
        {
            question: "8. What signifies the difference between Java and JavaScript?",
            option1: "Java creates applications that can run in any virtual machine (JVM) or browser while JavaScript was made as a programming language to make web pages interactive",
            option2: "javascript is a part of java to make web apps",
            option3: "Let me google it, i will find it on stackoverflow",
            option4: "JavaScript creates applications that can run in any virtual machine (JVM) or browser while Java was made as a programming language to make web pages interactive",
            correctresponse: "Java creates applications that can run in any virtual machine (JVM) or browser while JavaScript was made as a programming language to make web pages interactive",
            time: 1
        },
        {
            question: "9. Pick the wrong one",
            option2: "When a number is added to a string, the number type is always converted to the number type.",
            option1: "false, 0, 0n, -0, “”, null, undefined, and NaN are falsey values",
            option3: "OR (||) operator - If the first value is truthy, then the first value is returned. Otherwise, always the second value gets returned.",
            option4: "AND ( && ) operator - If both the values are truthy, always the second value is returned. If the first value is falsy then the first value is returned or if the second value is falsy then the second value is returned.",
            correctresponse: "When a number is added to a string, the number type is always converted to the number type.",
            time: 2
        },
        {
            question: "10. Which can used to access HTML elements using Javascript??",
            option1: "document.queryselector",
            option2: "document.getElementbyID",
            option3: "document.getElementById",
            option4: "document.querySelection",
            correctresponse: "document.getElementById",
            time: 1
        },
        {
            question: "11. typeof of NaN will return a Number.",
            option1: "To check if a value is NaN, we use the isNaN() function",
            option2: "NaN means not a number so NaN will not return a number",
            option3: "typeof NaN will not work on NaN",
            option4: "the statement in question and other options are wrong",
            correctresponse: "To check if a value is NaN, we use the isNaN() function",
            time: 1
        },
        {
            question: "12. Functions that are used as an argument to another function are called callback functions.",
            option1: "Callback functions are always cause callback hell",
            option2: "Functions that are used as an argument to another function are called fNfunctions.",
            option3: "Callback functions are constructor functions, which are used to create objects in javascript.",
            option4: "the statement in question is correct and option1, option2 and option3 are wrong",
            correctresponse: "the statement in question is correct and option1, option2 and option3 are wrong",
            time: 1
        }
        ,{
            question: "13. what is output of function add(num1, num2) {return arguments[0] + arguments[1];} and const add (num1, num2) =>{return arguments[0] + arguments[1];} for add(2,3)?",
            option1: "5,5",
            option2: "5,arguments not defined",
            option3: "arguments not defined,arguments not defined",
            option4: "arguments not defined,5",
            correctresponse: "5,arguments not defined",
            time: 1
        },
        {
            question: "14. What will be the output of console.log(typeof null)?",
            option1: "object",
            option2: "null",
            option3: "undefined",
            option4: "string",
            correctresponse: "object",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "15. Which method converts a JSON object to a string?",
            option1: "JSON.stringify()",
            option2: "JSON.parse()",
            option3: "JSON.toString()",
            option4: "String.JSON()",
            correctresponse: "JSON.stringify()",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "16. How can you create a new array from an existing array in ES6?",
            option1: "Using push()",
            option2: "Using slice()",
            option3: "Using spread operator [...]",
            option4: "Using splice()",
            correctresponse: "Using spread operator [...]",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "17. What is the result of '5' - 2?",
            option1: "3",
            option2: "'3'",
            option3: "'52'",
            option4: "NaN",
            correctresponse: "3",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "18. Which statement is true about const in JavaScript?",
            option1: "It creates a mutable reference to a value.",
            option2: "It creates an immutable reference to a value.",
            option3: "It prevents objects from being modified.",
            option4: "It can only store primitive types.",
            correctresponse: "It creates an immutable reference to a value.",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "19. What does the '===' operator check?",
            option1: "Value only",
            option2: "Data type only",
            option3: "Both value and data type",
            option4: "None of the above",
            correctresponse: "Both value and data type",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "20. What will the following code log? console.log(0.1 + 0.2 === 0.3);",
            option1: "true",
            option2: "false",
            option3: "undefined",
            option4: "NaN",
            correctresponse: "false",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "21. What is a closure in JavaScript?",
            option1: "A function combined with its lexical environment",
            option2: "A loop inside a function",
            option3: "A function without a return value",
            option4: "A method of encapsulating variables",
            correctresponse: "A function combined with its lexical environment",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "22. How do you declare a JavaScript function?",
            option1: "function myFunction()",
            option2: "function = myFunction()",
            option3: "function:myFunction()",
            option4: "var myFunction = function()",
            correctresponse: "function myFunction()",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "23. What is the output of console.log(2 + '2')?",
            option1: "22",
            option2: "4",
            option3: "'2'",
            option4: "undefined",
            correctresponse: "22",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "24. Which of the following is not a JavaScript framework?",
            option1: "React",
            option2: "Angular",
            option3: "Vue",
            option4: "Laravel",
            correctresponse: "Laravel",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "25. How do you remove the first element of an array in JavaScript?",
            option1: "array.pop()",
            option2: "array.shift()",
            option3: "array.splice(0, 1)",
            option4: "array.slice(1)",
            correctresponse: "array.shift()",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "26. What is the purpose of the isNaN function?",
            option1: "To check if a value is a number",
            option2: "To check if a value is not a number",
            option3: "To convert a value to a number",
            option4: "To parse a number from a string",
            correctresponse: "To check if a value is not a number",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "27. Which array method is used to add elements to the end of an array?",
            option1: "push()",
            option2: "pop()",
            option3: "unshift()",
            option4: "concat()",
            correctresponse: "push()",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "28. What will console.log(typeof NaN) output?",
            option1: "undefined",
            option2: "object",
            option3: "number",
            option4: "NaN",
            correctresponse: "number",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "29. Which JavaScript keyword is used to define variables?",
            option1: "var",
            option2: "let",
            option3: "const",
            option4: "All of the above",
            correctresponse: "All of the above",
            time: 1,
        },
        {
            question: "30. How can you check if an object has a property in JavaScript?",
            option1: "object.exists('property')",
            option2: "property in object",
            option3: "object.has('property')",
            option4: "object.contains('property')",
            correctresponse: "property in object",
            time: 1,
        },
    ],
    
}

export default javascriptquestions